A Guide to the Went Family Papers, 1806-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Went Family Papers, 1806-1864
The Library of Virginia
22834
27 leaves, negative photostats
Went Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 1948, by John Lee Pratt of Fredericksburg, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Went family was a prominent family in King George County, Virginia. They were related to the Kenyon and Ficklin families. The first James Went was a prominent local citizen and served as a captain in the Virginia militia. The second James Went moved first to Kentucky, then to Mississippi, where he was killed by a blow to the head with a brick.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1806-1864, of the Went family of King George County, Virginia, consisting of letters from family and friends describing life and agriculture in Mason County, Kentucky, and Adams County, Mississippi; providing news of the illnesses and deaths of relatives; commenting on the purchase of slaves; and sending other family and social news; also a letter, 27 August 1864, from Major Theodore G. Barker, Headquarters, Cavalry Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, to Colonel Richard Lee Turberville Beale (1819-1893), colonel of the 9th Virginia Cavalry, sending the praise of General Wade Hampton (1818-1902) to the command. Papers also include miscellaneous notes on family births and deaths, as well as the prices of various items; and an affidavit, 7 February 1854, of Berryman Cox and Stiles P. Curtis (1792-1860) of Spotsylvania County, Virginia, attesting to their service during the War of 1812.
Contents List
- Letter, 28 May 1806, from an unknown correspondent in Mason County, Kentucky, containing personal news about settling in Kentucky.
- Letter, 3 August 1813, from Joseph K. Ficklin (b. 1793) of Mason County to James Wint (Went) (1753-1830) of King Goerge County concerning personal news and agriculture in Kentucky.
- Letter, 29 August 1815, from James Went of Mason County to James Went of King George County discussing Went, senior's disappointment about Went, junior's settling in Kentucky.
- Letter, 16 January 1816, from James Went of Mason County to his sister, Polly Went of King George County sending greetings and commenting on agriculture and land in Kentucky.
- Letter, 29 December 1823, from James Went now of Adams County, Mississippi, to his sister Polly Went containing news of his health and situation.
- Letter, 22 April 1824, from James Went, Adams County, to his sister Polly Went containing news of his health and situation.
- Letter, 23 September 1824, from Henry Bruce (1777-1855) of Fleming County, Kentucky, to James Went of King George County discussing his travels and personal news.
- Letter, 20 October 1831, from George M. Graham of Alexandria, Virginia, to William F. Taliaferro (d. 1836) or Henry Went (ca. 1798-1837) of Westmoreland County, Virginia, concerning the purchase of slaves.
- Letter, 3 August 1833, from Henry Went to his sister concerning personal news.
- Miscellaneous notes, 1836, on the birth of a child and the prices of various items.
- Letter, 30 June 1837, from David B. Taylor to Jane Went (b. ca. 1770) informing her of her son's worsening health.
- Affidavit, 7 February 1854, of Berryman Cox and Stiles P. Curtis (1792-1860) of Spotsylvania County, Virginia, attesting to their service during the War of 1812.
- miscellaneous notes, no date and 1862, concerning the deaths of Henry Went and others.
- Letter, 27 August 1864, from Major Theodore G. Barker, Headquarters, Cavalry Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, to Colonel Richard Lee Turberville Beale (1819-1893), colonel of the 9th Virginia Cavalry, sending the praise of General Wade Hampton (1818-1902) to the command.
- Letter, no date, from William S. Allen of Jefferson County, Mississippi, to Polly Went informing her of the death of her brother James Went.
- Letter, no date, from Judith Ficklin (1772-1826) containing personal news.